CATS MEOW
MEOWING CONTINUES
Good morning.
I just need a little refreshment.
It was a long night.
I was thinking I could join
Kemal's interview.
I'm afraid to say I don't think
your presence would be helpful.
Why not? Well, you're foreign.
A little aggressive.
And, of course, you did chase
him halfway across Istanbul.
You're the boss. Yep.
I am, aren't I?
Can you confirm that you are
Kemal Haddad,
born in Beirut, Lebanon
on 18 August, 2003,
currently residing at
the Jevise hostel?
Did you know Gozde Serene?
What was the nature of
your relationship?
OK.
Can you explain
the large amounts of cocaine
that my colleagues found
in your room?
Did you kill her?
Why did you send...
..this text?
No.
No, I didn't send that.
She texted me, told me to meet her.
Can you prove that?
I lost my phone last night.
Why would you meet at a graveyard?
She thought it was safe.
No-one would see us.
Suleyman?
Why haven't you all left yet?
Selma didn't tell you?
About Gozde's fiance?
Uh-oh.
Oh, Selma.
This is our case.
Has to be.
Not until she says it is.
Let's have a look around and...
..avoid the Eye of Sauron,
if we can.
Well, the security
and encryption's first class.
We're not getting into his CCTV
or data any time soon.
That's a shame.
Would be lovely to see what
those cameras picked up.
Nevertheless...
Coast is clear. Shall we?
CATS MEOW ON PHONE
HE CHUCKLES
Sir.
Morning. How's it going?
Ikmen. Detective Suleyman.
There you go.
So, Butcher, who has Selma deemed
worthy of the case?
Inspector Jan is on his way.
Excellent. A very good man,
very good indeed.
Very good. Wonderful man.
But we're here to assist in
any way we possibly can.
I'm sure you don't mind. Huh?
Many hands make light work,
of course.
Yeah.
Hell of a struggle, eh?
There's blood and hair on this.
Let's check if it's Mesut's.
Of course, you know this.
Forensics won't be easy.
Mesut's party last night.
A lot of handshaking, back-slapping.
Plus, a night spent in
the pool's chlorine.
Difficult. Difficult.
And, even though we know
the cause of death...
..whoever strangled Mesut
covered their tracks well.
I don't envy Inspector Jan.
Difficult, difficult,
very difficult.
Boss? Ikmen!
Ah, yeah.
This isn't your crime scene.
You and your team need to leave.
Well, respectfully,
I feel there's a certain, erm,
link or two, faint resonance
with the Gozde Serene murder,
wouldn't you say?
Yes, you might be right.
However, right now, I need you
to focus on Gozde's murder.
Inspector Jan will lead
this investigation.
Well...
..all right.
By the way, the Serenes are asking
for Gozde's body back - for burial.
And I've had 50 phone calls
about Mesut just this morning.
So, please, clean this all up.
Quickly and quietly.
Certainly.
Thank you.
Thank you. Ahem.
Probably, you should tell Inspector
Jan he's no longer required.
Kemal's Forensics are back.
They found traces of Gozde's blood
under his fingernails.
The kid needs to talk.
You suspect he's guilty?
Definitely doesn't look good.
Yeah, no, it doesn't.
Well, regardless,
we need a new strategy with Kemal
if you want him to open up.
"We?" Yeah, "we".
Good work back there.
What are we doing here?
Beginning of the new strategy.
Hello. Oh, hi.
Cheechek.
Let's go.
Thank you.
I believe you've met
my colleague, Suleyman.
You must be hungry.
That's the cake from my
wife's birthday.
Ahh.
How's that? Ah!
Please.
Take your time.
We're not in a hurry.
Why's Gozde's blood on your skin?
Kemal, we have an
incriminating message from you
on Gozde's telephone.
Forensic evidence, the cocaine...
I understand you've had
a difficult life,
and your instinct tells you
to trust no-one.
Yeah?
Now, this is my passport...
..my government ID...
..the driving licence,
and my address.
My mother's maiden name was Yavuz.
My first pet was
a tabby cat called Bonchuk.
So, you're good with computers, no?
Now, with that information, you can
dismantle my life completely.
True?
Now, if, at any time,
you feel that I let you down,
you have my sincere permission
to do that.
Now, tell me how you met Gozde.
I've never settled here.
I was happy online.
I had friends.
I was good at something.
I started exploring.
Darker corners of the internet.
Yes, but just for fun.
Then I met Gozde's brother.
He got you a job with Mesut.
I was a waiter at these
private parties he threw.
A lot of rich guys, young women...
..alcohol, drugs.
And Gozde.
So I found her TikTok channel.
And, one night,
I sneaked some drinks
and went up to her
and offered to help her.
That was it.
I had never met anyone like her.
She was...the kind of girl that made
anything seem possible, you know?
Why did you meet her in the
graveyard that night?
We were going to escape Istanbul.
Her father said
she ended things with you.
Well, she changed her mind.
Mesut Calak was murdered
last night.
Where were you?
Hiding in Vefa.
So, first Gozde's killed,
then her fiance's strangled,
thrown in a pool with
their engagement photo.
That seems like someone
wasn't happy about their marriage.
FIST POUNDS TABLE
I told you they were not going
to get married.
She loved me.
So what did you do, huh?
When you failed to secure
the Canadian visa?
You're starting a new life.
You needed money,
which explains the cocaine.
Where did you get it?
We sold a lot of cocaine.
We sold it for Cai Ze Lop,
to all his friends and connections.
One night, when he was out of it,
and the safe was open,
Gozde just put it in her bag.
That simple.
That's what got her killed.
They were watching her.
So you think Cai Ze Lop killed Gozde
and then Mr Calak?
So, if that's the case...
..why is Gozde's blood on your skin?
I had to touch her one last time.
Were those your real documents?
Of course.
What do you make of Kemal's story?
It doesn't seem credible to me.
Mm.
PHONE RINGS
Selma, how nice to hear from you.
I'm going to charge Kemal with
possession with intent to supply,
and Gozde's murder.
Excellent, excellent.
But may I suggest
you hold off a moment?
Let us try to link him conclusively
to Mr Calak's death too
and tie the entire matter up
with a ribbon
that you can present to the press.
Fine.
Thank you, Selma. Thank you.
Oh, dear...
And how are we going to conclusively
link Kemal to Mesut's death?
We're not. Come on.
Cai Ze Lop is inside.
Do you want to go in?
No.
Let's keep a watchful eye for now.
Well, Detective?
Where are you going?
I have a tickle in the
back of my brain.
So, what are we doing here?
I got a statement from
one of Mr Calak's staff.
He saw Cai Ze Lop's G-Wagon
in front of his house last night.
Did Ikmen not tell you?
Of course he didn't.
BUZZER RINGS
Jahit.
WOMAN CHANTS
MEHMET: So who is this guy?
Cai Ze Lop?
He showed up on the radar
a few years ago.
Supposedly the city's biggest
drug trafficker now,
but you know how hard it is
to make that stick.
Those are gun bags.
Yes, they are.
ENGINE STARTS
I think he's heading to the water.
Maybe he's going to dump the car.
Destroy any forensics.
I don't like this.
Something's off.
We don't have a choice, my friend.
We can't lose that car.
What? Damn it!
TYRES SCREECH
Where did they go?
Ayse, we need to get out of here.
Shut up and let me think.
I'll take a look.
You call for backup.
AYSE:
Suleyman!
PHONE VIBRATES
I thought we were friends,
Detective.
After all, I did you a big favour
last night with the Lebanese kid.
Did you also kill Mr Calak
last night?
Strange question. Why do you ask?
One of your cars was
ID'd in his compound.
I had him driven home.
He was unsettled after your
superior had spoken to him.
Why were you watching Gozde Seren?
I do my best to know everything
about everyone.
Yeah, evidently.
Relationships can be mutually
beneficial.
I help Calak, he helps me.
If I help you...
No, that's not going to happen.
Poor strategy, Detective.
This is not quid pro quo.
You give me the information,
that's it.
End of transaction, we go home.
I like you, detective. You're brave.
Look, The night Godze died
I am told that
she paid a visit to
Sirkeci train station first.
My men lost her in the crowd,
but you might be interested
to know why she went.
Perhaps we'll speak again one day.
You never know when a man with
information can be useful to you.
Especially when those closest
to you are concealing things.
What do you mean?
That's the end of the
complimentary appetisers.
But, please, stop by the
restaurant
when you're ready to
pay for your meal, hmm?
HE HANGS UP PHONE
SHE SIGHS
Who was that?
Cai Ze Lop.
We need Tarik.
HE SNIGGERS
WATER RUNNING
I'm looking at the footage now.
Anything?
She's got to be there somewhere.
Nothing yet.
PHONE RINGING, CAT MEOWING
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
Got her.
I'm sending something now.
What's she doing?
That's her escape bag.
So what happened to her?
The cemetery is near the water.
Let's get a diving team.
SHE WEEPS AND MUTTERS
MUSIC PLAYS
MUSIC STOPS
So you killed him?
And you threw the photo in the pool,
make it look like Kemal did it.
SHE SUCKS TEETH
Selma won't want to lose face.
Well, I think we're all done here
for the day.
Cool.
Hey. We did good.
All of us. Yeah.
CAR HORN HONKS
Mehmet.
Mehmet!
Dad.
I was in town on business and...
..I wondered,
maybe we could have dinner?
I tried calling, but... Yeah.
Sorry, um, things are hectic.
Thank you for the basket.
I get it.
It's a new job. You're trying to
get your foot in the door, right?
Mm.
God, I mean, I can't believe
it's you, Mehmet.
HE CHUCKLES
How long has it been?
A long time.
You realise that wasn't...
I mean, please tell me you know
that.
Your mother was a bit...
Yeah, I know.
Look, I'm off to mosque.
I'm sorry you came all this way.
Another time? Yeah.
You go. I'll come back later.
These articles not ringing
any bells?
Anything at all, Leyla?
Nothing.
I'm sorry.
I barely remember anything
about being here.
Like, the city?
Yeah, it's my city.
And all the summers here
as a kid but...
..but this stuff, it's...
it's gone.
You want to find out what happened
to me, don't you?
I'm going to try.
I'm sorry I can't help.
Not yet.
Right. "Not yet."
SHE SIGHS
I wish I knew why I left London.
Me too.
No, nothing.
FOGHORN WAILS IN DISTANCE
HORN HONKS
You know anything about him?
Why do you ask?
After Leyla and I broke up,
she lived here and I was in London,
I may have...
..engaged in a light bit of
Instagram surveillance.
He used to like and comment
on everything she posted.
And then after the hit-and-run,
deleted his account.
Were they...
..together?
I liked him.
Ouch.
What can I say?
He liked my food.
He used to bring me flowers.
But...
..you're right.
Now, nothing.
Jacob Crews.
Hey.
I'm a friend of Leyla Pamuk's.
Who?
Auntie Hulya will be sad
you forgot her dolmades so easily.
Man, she talked about you a lot.
Is she still alive?
You broke her heart, you know?
Yeah.
Well, I'm trying to make amends.
Of course.
You want to find out what happened.
Well, you must think
I'm a coward.
Have you ever considered the idea
that it was just an accident? No.
I don't think you have either. Or
else you wouldn't have gone ghost.
What was Leyla investigating?
I don't know. Truly.
She didn't tell you anything?
I'm sorry, listen,
we do good work here.
We help. I won't jeopardise that
for anyone.
Not even Leyla.
You don't care about her at all.
Of course I do.
I really don't know what you think
you're going to achieve here,
all by yourself.
My conscience...is clear.
Kayra Khan?
What are you all doing?
You're late.
What's going on?
Oh. Whoa, no.
Cahit confessed. Why are you
looking at Lokman's interview?
Cahit is protecting Lokman.
You're actually out of your mind.
How could Cahit fake a message
on Gozde's phone from Kemal?
Spyware.
Guy was a controlling psychopath.
Yeah, Tarik did find spyware on
Gozde's phone. But the problem is
there was a message sent
from Kemal's phone as well.
Do you think it's plausible
that Cahit put spyware
on Gozde and Kemal's phone?
So what do you think happened?
Cahit killed Mesur Calak
because of the business dispute.
But it was Lokman who killed Gozde.
We have been digging into him
chasing down some weird
debit card transactions.
Here's his bank statement.
Some strange purchases.
Cosmetics, hair products.
Cosmetics? OK, so,
solid evidence, then? Jesus Christ.
You know what we do have?
CCTV footage of Lokman
halfway across Istanbul
at the time of the murder. I know.
Yeah, bring it up, then.
So... There we go.
Wait.
Unpause it.
Lockman's left-handed.
Whoever went to the hostel
that night isn't.
So maybe Lokman faked that, too.
I'm going to analyse this right now.
Have you looked at these?
No, we just got those.
Lokman's making a bomb.
Uncuff him.
Kemal, Look at me.
We are going to help you, I swear,
but right now I need to tell you
something really important.
And you need to tell me everything
about your friendship with Lokman,
OK? Yeah? Yeah.
Are you sure? I mean,
I knew he was angry, but this?
No, I know, but right now you need
to concentrate and you need to think
of anything that might help us
find him. Anything.
Mrs Seren.
PHONE BUZZES
Yep. Kemal says he's the one
that got Lokman into the dark web.
He knows his usernames, passwords,
everything, he just needs a laptop.
Whatever he needs, do it.
OK, just log in. Mm-hm.
Whoa.
What is it?
Ayse. OK, boss, Lokman is into
some really dark stuff, OK?
Kemal found a whole bunch of posts
on misogynist incel forums.
He's posted, like,
an anti-female manifesto,
says he's going to martyr himself
for the male cause,
and he's rigged up a live stream
so the whole world can watch.
Where is he?
He's at the community centre.
Gozde's memorial. Let's go.
Welcome, everybody.
This week has been devastating.
You're going to do great.
Gozde Seren was one of us.
Her death, her murder,
it highlights everything
our action group
has said since day one.
MICROPHONE CUTS OFF
Um...can you hear me?
What are you doing?
I've come for the memorial.
Smile, everybody.
SCREAMING
Sit down! Sit back down!
Go back to your seats.
Sit down!
I need to tell you about Gozde.
This is all my fault.
This way.
The main doors are locked.
He hacked the system.
Ayse alerted SWAT. ETA ten minutes.
This makes me sick!
You're all worshipping
this hypocrite,
wearing a scarf,
pretending to be a respectful girl,
and then whoring herself
behind her fiance's back!
You're all hypocrites.
She wasn't one of you.
You're just using her death
for your feminist, feminazi cause.
SHOUTING INSIDE
There is also a narrow space under
the stage where we can access... No,
it's too dangerous,
you might spook him.
PHONE BUZZES
It's going viral.
In a few seconds it'll be too late.
We are going in.
SWAT will bring a negotiator.
He doesn't want to negotiate.
He's putting on a show.
You're too emotionally invested.
Can you take my friend
to that place under the stage?
This is... Detective.
I need you to trust me.
Please go, go.
POUNDING ON DOOR
Inspector Cetin Ikmen.
I thought you wanted
to debate a feminist?
Well, I volunteer.
Anyone comes in from behind you
or you shoot me,
I let go, we all die.
OK, it's a deal.
So...what are we discussing?
The fact that there is more of us
than there are of them.
So is that why you killed Gozde?
Revolution requires sacrifice.
I have to confess,
I don't want to debate.
There.
I just want you to question,
if you go through with this,
whether it'll work.
I mean, will you be able to inspire
your brothers to rise up
against women when they find out
you didn't want to take any credits
for what you had done?
In fact,
you went to a lot of trouble
to ensure your friend Kemal did.
So, is this really
for the incel cause
or...jealousy
masquerading as martyrdom?
You don't get it.
You're too old and too stupid.
You can't fathom the rage
I'll unleash when I do this.
I'm sorry. Cicek!
This is just stupid.
This isn't about Gozde. It's not...
It's not even about women.
You just need attention. Why?
Your father.
Lokman, your father, you think
your father never noticed you,
never loved you
as he did your sister?
But let me tell you, your father
would do anything for you.
I'm very sorry that your father
made you feel that you don't matter.
Take it from me,
you are the only thing that does.
Lokman, that man would confess
to his own daughter's murder
for you.
You just...don't...get it!
Of course, I can't...
How could I possibly comprehend
what it is like to be you?
To grow up in this world
that we've given you.
We are failures.
This is a damaged planet
we're handing over to you.
When I look at you,
any of you, all I see is hope.
So...
..we can fix this, really.
Come on, we can really fix this.
Cicek!
Watch the trigger,
his finger pressed down.
Thank you, Kemal. Thank you.
Hi, Dad. Yeah, it's me.
You know, let's do something.
NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE
DOOR BUZZES
So...what's next?
I don't know.
Stay in Istanbul, I guess.
Not much for me here,
but there is nothing anywhere else.
I'm going to help you however I can.
But I'm going to need
something from you.
You ever heard of Kayra Khan?
MUSIC: 21 / Queen
by Elanur